我们为何站立
Humans are among the very few creatures who stand on two legs
人类是站立在两条腿上的极少数生物之一
We take it for granted
我们认为这是理所当然的
but being upright is quite a skill
但是直立是很巧妙的事
Take a normal four-legged chair simple, stable
拿一把普通的四腿椅子简单，稳定
or even a three-legged stool
甚至三足凳
but try a two-legged seat...
但是试试两脚座位…
Human babies spend around 2000 hours in their first year
人类婴儿在一岁时花费大约2000个小时
developing the coordination and strength to stand
培养协调能力和站立能力
It's the same amount of time an Olympic athlete
这和一名奥林匹克运动员
puts into a year training
一年里接受训练的时间一样
Standing up is a major achievement, not only in our lives
站起来不仅是我们生活中的一项重大成就
but also in human evolution
而且在人类进化中
Why did we do this?
我们为什么要这样做？
We'll probably never know for sure
我们可能永远无法确定
But there's no shortage of theories
但是不乏有理论
Hunters needing to take food home from the site of a kill
猎人需要将食物从杀戮现场带回家
or conserve energy to outrun other animals
或节省能量超过其他动物
Perhaps it was to carry and protect babies or was it for sexual display?
也许是为了携带和保护婴儿，还是为了进行性展示？
Some say it was our environment, as forests died back
有人说这是我们的环境，因为森林灭绝
it became easier to find food by walking than by climbing
走路比爬山更容易找到食物
And the higher your head, the further you can see
登的越高，看得越远
Plus being upright means less of your body
直立意味着更少的身躯
exposed to the midday African sun
暴露在中午的非洲阳光下
So maybe we stood up just to stay cool
也许我们站起来只是为了保持凉爽
There is agreement on one thing
在一件事上达成了共识
standing freed our hands
站立解放了我们的双手
to become immensely sensitive and versatile tools
成为极为敏感和通用的工具
and with that came a big increase in brain capacity
随之而来的是大脑能力的极大提高
So from many points of view, standing is clearly a very good idea
因此，从许多角度来看，站立显然是一个非常好的主意
giving us a whole new level of control and power
给我们全新的控制和力量
However, out of the millions of species on this planet
但是，在这个星球上数以百万计的物种中
being a permanent biped is incredibly rare
成为永久性两足动物的情况极为罕见
Some animals, baboons and bears, meerkats and chimpanzees
一些动物，狒狒和熊，猫鼬和黑猩猩
can occasionally pull off a two-legged trick but permanently?
偶尔会耍两腿的把戏，但会保持永久吗？
Something we share with only a very few creatures on Earth
我们与地球上只有极少数生物共享的东西
Like some obscure rodents
就像一些不知名的啮齿动物
wallabies, ostriches and the giant pangolin
小袋鼠，鸵鸟和巨型穿山甲
It turns out this biped thing is quite tricky
事实证明，此两足动物的动作非常棘手
Think of the robots...
想想机器人…
tech companies have invested massively to crack this problem
科技公司已投入大量资金来解决这个问题
of how you get a robot standing up on two legs
如何使机器人站立在两条腿上
and the Daleks? They don't even try
那戴立克呢？他们甚至不尝试
Daleks：《神秘博士》中的金属机器人，宇宙里最强大、最具侵略性的种族之一。
So while they can destroy the universe
因此，尽管它们可以摧毁宇宙
they can't chase the Doctor up a flight of stairs
他们无法将博士追上楼梯
We pay a high physical price for our standing
我们为站立付出了高昂的身体代价
chronic strain to our backs and our knees
背部和膝盖的慢性疲劳
Truth is, standing may give us power
事实是，站着可以给我们力量
but it comes with exposure and vulnerability
但是它带有风险和脆弱性
and that's what opens it up to manipulation
这就是打开它进行操纵的原因
Here's an example, man and woman standing, simple
这是一个例子，男人和女人站着，简单
But is it? Let's take a look at how they're standing
但是吗？让我们看看他们的站立情况
The man standing firm, planted on two legs,
那个稳稳站着的男人，用两条腿
The woman, precariously balanced on just one
那个女人，单腿站立
What does that tell us?
这告诉我们什么？
In every culture you can find different ways that society
在每种文化中，都可以找到不同的方式
tries to teach us when to stand, when not to stand
试图教我们什么时候站着，什么时候不站着
Politicians play on our hopes and fears
政治家操纵我们的希望和恐惧
by telling us that we are broken or on our knees and that they are alone
通过告诉我们我们已经受伤或屈膝，他们独傲
have that magic that will make us stand tall and proud once more
拥有使我们站起来的魔力
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
团结则存
我不理解
昂首屹立
In fact we're so obsessed about standing
事实上，我们是如此着迷于站立
We talk about it all the time without even realizing
我们一直在谈论它，甚至没有意识到
How we stand also speaks volumes about how we're feeling
我们的立场也充分说明了我们的感受
So no wonder many public speakers
所以难怪有很多演说家
like to hide their legs behind a podium
喜欢把腿藏在讲台后面
because how you're standing can reveal too much
因为你的站立方式可以透露太多
If you see someone looping one leg behind the other
如果您看到有人在另一条腿上缠绕一条腿
half balanced on that point
在这一点上平衡一半
you're going to wonder insecure, uncertain?
你会怀疑不安全，是这样吗？
or if you see someone with their hip jutted out
或者如果您看到某人的臀部被突出
you might read that as quite a sexual statement
您可能会认为这是很色情的说法
Hands on hips?
手放在臀部？
Is that reinforcing core strength and powerful
是增强核心力量和力量吗
or is it perhaps defensive?
还是防御性的？
Slouching, well, quite clearly you're not exactly on top of the situation
懒散，很明显，您并没有完全掌握最新情况
Changing the way you stand can actually change the way you feel
改变你的站立方式实际上可以改变你的感受
and how others feel about you
以及别人对你的看法
But beware, if your stance doesn't look genuine
但是请注意，如果你的立场看起来并不真实
it may invite mockery
它可能会引起嘲笑
Own the way you stand
拥有自己的立场
Standing is not only a state of body
站立不仅是身体的状态
it's a state of mind
这是一种心境